{
	"cards": [
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-20-tag-vocabulary-card-1",
			"front": "The buildup of excess acid in the blood or body tissues that can result from a primary illness.",
			"back": "acidosis"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-20-tag-vocabulary-card-2",
			"front": "A metabolic disorder in which the ability to metabolize carbohydrates (sugars) is impaired, usually because of a lack of insulin.",
			"back": "diabetes mellitus"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-20-tag-vocabulary-card-3",
			"front": "A form of hyperglycemia in uncontrolled diabetes in which certain acids accumulate when insulin is not available.",
			"back": "diabetic ketoacidosis"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-20-tag-vocabulary-card-4",
			"front": "Glands that secrete or release chemicals that are used inside the body.",
			"back": "endocrine glands"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-20-tag-vocabulary-card-5",
			"front": "The complex message and control system that integrates many body functions, including the release of hormones.",
			"back": "endocrine system"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-20-tag-vocabulary-card-6",
			"front": "One of the basic sugars; it is the primary fuel, in conjunction with oxygen, for cellular metabolism.",
			"back": "glucose"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-20-tag-vocabulary-card-7",
			"front": "The study and prevention of blood-related disorders.",
			"back": "hematology"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-20-tag-vocabulary-card-8",
			"front": "A hereditary condition in which the patient lacks one or more of the blood’s normal clotting factors.",
			"back": "hemophilia"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-20-tag-vocabulary-card-9",
			"front": "Substances formed in specialized organs or glands and carried to another organ or group of cells in the same organism; they regulate many body functions, including metabolism, growth, and body temperature.",
			"back": "hormones"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-20-tag-vocabulary-card-10",
			"front": "An abnormally high blood glucose level.",
			"back": "hyperglycemia"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-20-tag-vocabulary-card-11",
			"front": "A life-threatening condition resulting from high blood glucose that typically occurs in older adults and which causes altered mental status, dehydration, and organ damage.",
			"back": "hyperosmolar hyperglycemic nonketotic syndrome"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-20-tag-vocabulary-card-12",
			"front": "An abnormally low blood glucose level.",
			"back": "hypoglycemia"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-20-tag-vocabulary-card-13",
			"front": "A hormone produced by the islets of Langerhans (endocrine gland located throughout the pancreas) that enables glucose in the blood to enter cells; used in synthetic form to treat and control diabetes mellitus.",
			"back": "insulin"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-20-tag-vocabulary-card-14",
			"front": "Deep, rapid breathing; usually the result of an accumulation of certain acids when insulin is not available in the body.",
			"back": "Kussmaul respirations"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-20-tag-vocabulary-card-15",
			"front": "Excessive thirst that persists for long periods despite reasonable fluid intake; often the result of excessive urination.",
			"back": "polydipsia"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-20-tag-vocabulary-card-16",
			"front": "Excessive eating; in diabetes, the inability to use glucose properly can cause a sense of hunger.",
			"back": "polyphagia"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-20-tag-vocabulary-card-17",
			"front": "The passage of an unusually large volume of urine in a given period; in diabetes, this can result from the wasting of glucose in the urine.",
			"back": "polyuria"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-20-tag-vocabulary-card-18",
			"front": "A hereditary disease that causes normal, round red blood cells to become oblong, or sickle shaped.",
			"back": "sickle cell disease"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-20-tag-vocabulary-card-19",
			"front": "A state of unconsciousness resulting from several problems, including ketoacidosis, dehydration because of excessive urination, and hyperglycemia.",
			"back": "symptomatic hyperglycemia"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-20-tag-vocabulary-card-20",
			"front": "Severe hypoglycemia resulting in changes in mental status.",
			"back": "symptomatic hypoglycemia"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-20-tag-vocabulary-card-21",
			"front": "A tendency toward the development of blood clots as a result of an abnormality of the system of coagulation.",
			"back": "thrombophilia"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-20-tag-vocabulary-card-22",
			"front": "A blood clot, either in the arterial or venous system. When the clot occurs in a cerebral artery, it may result in the interruption of cerebral blood flow and subsequent stroke.",
			"back": "thrombosis"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-20-tag-vocabulary-card-23",
			"front": "An autoimmune disorder in which the individual’s immune system produces antibodies to the pancreatic beta cells, and therefore the pancreas cannot produce insulin; onset in early childhood is common.",
			"back": "type 1 diabetes"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-20-tag-vocabulary-card-24",
			"front": "A condition in which insulin resistance develops in response to increased blood glucose levels; can be managed by exercise and diet modification, but is often managed by medications.",
			"back": "type 2 diabetes"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-20-tag-vocabulary-card-25",
			"front": "Ischemia and pain caused by sickle-shaped red blood cells that obstruct blood flow to a portion of the body.",
			"back": "vasoocclusive crisis"
		}
	],
	"category": {
		"value": "chapter-20",
		"label": "Chapter 20"
	},
	"tags": [
		{
			"value": "vocabulary",
			"label": "Vocabulary"
		}
	]
}